Aloha and welcome to week two. So this week we're going to talk about file management
and I do have a little page up here where you're already on but basically I'm replacing the video
here with one this one that I just created and talk a little bit about why bother with file
management. Okay for me it saves me time so I can find stuff easier. There are AI tools out there
now where you can get have them do things like organize all your photos and all that's doing
is managing your photos and grouping them in such a way to make it easier for you to find them.
Okay and that's all that I believe the most important part of file management is.
Now you might think well I never have
more than a couple hundred files that kind of stuff. Well I'm here to tell you that can change
and so you need good habits now just in case. For example let's look at this
printout here and let me grab the magnifying glass. I'm gonna blow it up a little bit so you
can see it. So this is a program for a Windows program it's called WinDirStat and what it does
is it cycles through all your files.
On your hard drive okay so here's my hard drive it's a C drive it has 48% free it's a 2 gig 2
terabyte drive 48% free and if you look over here I have 1.6 million files on this drive
okay of which a million of them are in my user directory and if we look in there
you can see that my main user is the first one under the line is essentially
the whole all million of those are in that directory. So now I have a million
files in my user directory. How do I find anything? I can search but sometimes
search takes a long time. All right and so if I have them organized in a
structured way I can narrow down the search parameters faster like only
search this directory or only search half of this directory or that
kind of thing. So and the reason why I say that is because when I look at my
drive okay my computer I have a C drive a D drive which is another terabyte an E
drive which is 3 terabytes an F drive which is 500 gigs a G drive which is 250
gigs and an H drive which is a terabyte. So I have all those have varying number
of different files.
on them. If I try to search all those for something it does take quite a while
okay for a search to work and then I don't even know if I'm getting the right
answer or finding the file I'm actually looking for. Alright so to me file
management is an important concept and that's why we're gonna go over it first.
Okay one key here is archive don't hoard. I'm a little bit of a hoarder. I'll just
be honest with you i'm a little bit of order but you need to get rid of things you don't need in
the future now sometimes you don't know if you don't need it so you may want to keep it or may
not want to all right and then there's a little bit about windows so everything in this book
is on windows and mac has a similar thing to file explorer it's called finder on your mac
and you can do pretty much all the same things okay it's just slightly different in terms of
where they're at and how you do them but essentially you can do the same thing
all right so that's um
kind of the introduction to why i think
when file management is important file and folder management so what i want you to do
regardless of whether you're mac or pc i would like you to read this section
of the textbook and you don't have to read everything in it but i think this section does
a decent job of going over the basics of file management
okay so there's a little bit of getting started managing your files saving a file to your pc
or to one drive or to google drive or to some other cloud storage how to create a folder how
to rename a folder
how to save a folder
movie movie move and copy files in folders okay so it's all the basics of
working with file management and all this stuff you can do on a Mac as well
okay using finder all right so I don't want this to be really a long video here
but just wanted you to say that file management to me is important and then
you have a file management assignment to do and basically what I want you to do
is create a structure that looks like this you have a documents folder on both
a Mac and a PC and then within that make a schoolwork folder and then within that
make a C to C 104 folder and then within that make an assignments folder okay so
you have one four folders okay all nested inside each other
you
okay so if I were to go to documents and I'm looking for an assignment from this
class I would drill down and go into my schoolwork and then go into this
specific class okay so if you ever look at my folders I have this is my folders
I have College folder I have courses I have all the courses and then with each
course have things broken down by semester sometimes and by type of thing
so I can find stuff okay and then you'd be able to do each of those and then you
would be able to run your F hatch and you don't need to do the same thing over and
over again a place where you can simply prepare theuctric test kingdom hacemos
find content I think you would get down to the tables when you're doing the test
it's you couldn't sign up online that's your key I would take the documents you
you'd have assignments and you might have readings you might have other
stuff in there and then all you do is you build it and you take a screenshot
okay if you're using a PC I suggest you use it's called snipping tool if you
don't know what it is you just go in here and just search for snipping tool
okay bring it up you click new it grays out your screen you click and drag what
you want there's your thing you save it and then you upload that file on a Mac
it's a command shift 4 for partial so if you want to I mean it's shift command 4
so all three of those keys shift command and then hit the 4 and then you just
click and drag your mouse click on one corner drag your mouse the other corner
of the picture you want to take it saves it to your desktop and then you just
upload that to the file
all right and that's all you have to do for this week and then just as a prep
that next week we're going to start and I don't have it set up properly yet
we're gonna start introduction a word okay and there'll be another start here
but it'll be about that assignment and you'll have two assignments
to do next week and I'll explain it next week and that should show up earlier
than this one probably like Thursday Friday of this week I decide when I'm
gonna have them posted but they're all well from now on starting with week 3
they won't show up on Monday they should show up before the weekend before the
weekend before that week okay so like Thursday or Friday they'll show week 3 we'll show up this week.
Thursday or Friday week four will show up the following Thursday or Friday for
anybody that wants to that's feeling like they want to work ahead a little
bit all right okay thanks and good luck this week and let me know if you have
any questions or issues bye